Michael Agranovskiy

Senior Software Developer

Tel Aviv

⑤ +972 53 863 2404

☑ csagranovskiy@gmail.com
⑥ agrml.github.io/me/

For more than 5 years I develop software with an urge to help people solve their problems. I develop product rather than close issues. Proactivity, empathy, focusing on the product result, end-user experience, and runtime stability – these are the qualities I value most both in colleagues and myself. Do we match?

Skills summary

Pro-level Backend development [Python/Django/asyncio/PyTest, PostgreSQL, Docker]

Mid-level Kubernets, Elastic Search. Mentoring. Team leading

Languages English (fluent), Russian (mothertongue)

Professional Experience

2021–2021 **BestDoctor**, Senior backend dev in the medical insurance sphere.

 $Python/Django/PyTest,\ Docker,\ zero-code\ intergrations$

- Implemented multiple features in a huge Django Admin with a bit of JS
- Solved a problem by a paid service instead of a month of coding from scratch

2020–2021 **Domclick (Sberbank)**, Tech lead and backend dev in a new buildings storefront.

Python/asyncio/FastAPI/PyTest, Docker, Kubernets, PostgreSQL, Elastic

- Improved stability, performance, test-coverage and architecture of several micro-services
- o Introduced SRE practices (monitorings, safe migrations) and processes on keeping them go
- o Improved work processes, e.g. made scrum work as much as it was possible.
- Closely worked with the product manager (designed principal implementations; helped to fit features to sprints)

2018–2020 **Yandex**, Backend development in the intranet department.

Python/Django/Celery/PyTest, Docker, PostgreSQL/YQL

- Worked with more than 10 projects, mainly with the internal hiring system.
- Increased Yandex employee hiring rate and decreased leaving rate by developing reference giving system and employee rotation system
- Launched a negotiation service. Designed a state machine for creating a new negotiation.
- Leaded migration to a new PaaS. Improved 5 affected libs/tools, migrated 3 projects myself, managed migration of 10 other projects.
- Mentored in Yandex Backend Development school

2016–2017 ARCCN, RnD in the field of Software-Defined Networking.

- Developed of a link state monitoring system (C++, Python. BFD, OpenFlow protocols)
- Designed a rule caching system for OpenFlow software switches (C, Intel DPDK. P4 protocol)

Education

2014–2018 Bachelor of Computer Science, Moscow State University.

Department of Computational Mathematics and Cybernetics

Publications and teaching

- 2021 "Developing backend using Django," an online course author and lecturer: https://bit.ly/34677lh
- 2021 "The way I develop software," an article on Medium [RU]: https://bit.ly/3kqJicl
- $\,$ "Using hash functions to accelerate performance of OpenFlow switches," Agranovskiy M., Shalimov A. // Program systems and toolware, MSU, 2017